Zachary Lineman

zachary.lineman0@gmail.com | (610) 850 - 5071 | Rochester New

LINKS PROFILE

github.com/ActuallyZach linkedin.com/in/zacharylineman/ https://actuallyzach.com

I am an independent iOS Developer currently studying at Rochester Institute of Technology. I am interested in all fields of Computer Science, from language development to cyber security. When I am interested in a topic I will take the time to research and become proficient in that field of study.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Highly Proficient

EXPERIENCE

Swift

RIT Electrical Vehicle Team — 2022-Present

UIKit

Firmware Engineer, Emulator Development, cross-team communication

iOS Development iOS System Libraries

BrickHack Logistics Team - 2022-Present

Logistics team member, Hackathon Management, Communication and Email skills

Proficient

SwiftUI

Independent iOS Contractor — 2020-Present

TypeScript / Javascript NodeJS

C++

Firebase

Python & Django Svelte & SvelteKit

Java

Completed full iOS Apps, iOS message extensions / apps, single page mockups in SwiftUI, full app rewrites from UIKit to Swift all exceeding customer's expectations. Led a team through a full stack rewrite of an iOS app, moved from UIKit to SwiftUI, as well as upgrading a NodeJS backend and implementing a secondary Python backend.

Shopper, Giant Direct, Pottstown PA — 2020-Present Tumblr #CODRS Blog — 2021

Knowledgeable

Selected by Tumblr to blog about Apple's WWDC 2021 conference.

Unity & Unreal Engine Framework Development Firmware Development **App Store Release Process**

Developer, Clear Spaces — 2020

Assisted in developing Clear Spaces iOS app in Swift using the SwiftUI and WidgetKit Framework. Major work on rewriting the photo cropping algorithm.

EDUCATION

LEADERSHIP

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Rochester Institute of Technology — Student 2022-Present

Learning New Skills Team Management Technical Support Community Management Cross-team and inter team communication

Eagle Scout Project

Planned, managed, and led an Eagle Scout project to enhance a local community park's trails. Directed large teams of people through the construction process. Handled all communication with the Parks and Recreation Committee.

AWARDS

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Jellycuts - https://jellycuts.com

German Honor Society

Developed the Jellycuts iOS App, an integrated development environment and programming language for the iOS Shortcuts app. Uses a custom NodeJS backend server and is written in Swift, SwiftUI and UIKit.

SCUM Map - https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id1515805855

A map app for the computer game SCUM. I worked with a business partner, Ed Sarkissian (https://esark.me) to create this app. The app is written using Firebase, Swift and UIKit.

Firefly - https://github.com/ActuallyZach/Firefly

An open source syntax highlighter for iOS, iPadOS, and macOS. Lead maintainer of the project, in charge of reviewing and integrating all pull requests into the project.

TEAM PROJECTS

OJR Tech Pac - https://oirtpac.com

Tech Pac is a club founded during the Covid-19 pandemic focused at the students and community. Wrote public facing and internal software to help the club achieve its goals.